In this video, we are going to be deploying a web link to devices using Microsoft Intune.
So, a web link is just a simple URL link that can be deployed to devices.
For example, if I go to my Windows 10 on the device here, and I go to my start menu.
And then, for example, we can see CNN as a link.
So this is actually being deployed using Microsoft Intune.
So let me go back again to Intune and from my Microsoft Endpoints monitor.
I just click apps.
And from the apps, we are going to actually go to all apps.
And then click add.
So here we are going to actually select a web link.
Here you can see on the order, you can select a web link, I just select that and then click
select.
So by selecting web links, so let's say, for example, we want to deploy the web link
of Udemy to all our devices.
So I'm just going to actually just put this in the mail and the description I'm going for
this, and I'm just going to enter you to the mail.com.
So the publisher is going to be Udemy.
For example, if I go to, let me just go to the website of Udemy.com and hit enter.
So what I want to do is, I want to actually deploy the following link to all my devices.
So I'm going to go back to my endpoint and I'm going to enter the URL, just enter control
fee.
So I require the manager product to open this link, I'm going to leave that to know.
The category, we're going to actually just let me just put that for business and then
show this as a future app in the company portal.
I want to see yes, because I want to give the user the opportunity to install it themselves
if they need it.
I'm going to click next.
And then when next, I'm going to see assignments, I want to actually see available for
all devices.
I'm going to see add all users and then I'm going to click next and then we can just
review and then click create.
So now I'm going to actually save this application and then what you're going to do now is
actually speed the deployment and we'll go to devices, all devices.
And here, you just want to actually make the device online, for example, you are working
for a company and then you can go to your, for example, one of those devices and then click
sync, back click is sync is going to actually sync all the policies and the deployment.
You just create it right now to that device, you got to do the same for other devices and
they can go to the device and check if the web link with those deploy is now available
on that device.
So after some time now, let me go back again to my Windows device here and you can see
we now have you do me a link, it says featured apps and you can see you do me, we can
actually just click on it and then we can now install.
So it's not actually a software just a link which after installation is going to be displayed
here on your start menu and then we can now see the link here.
So if I go back, let me go to my Windows device, you can see this is actually downloaded
and it's been installed and then if I go to my Windows 11 device, you can see we have
the same to that you do me a link, it's available, we can decide to just click on it
and then click install.
So this is the result process we take so few minutes, let's just wait for that to install
and then we can come back again.
So here you can see that this is actually being downloaded right now, if I go back again
to my Windows 10, one of my Windows 10 device, you can see it's installed.
So if I go to my start menu and then let me just scroll down for to search for you do
me, here you can see there we have the you do me a link, of course it's going to open
with Microsoft Edge because that is my default browser.
So you can see it takes me automatically to you do me a link, which of course it's going
to open to your Microsoft Edge and for the others it's going to still download, you can
see it's downloading and that will should take that much of time.